<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sam X.</title>
    <link>http://samx.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sam X.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://samx.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Daddy, what do you do at work?</title>
      <link>http://samx.io/post/daddy-what-do-you-do-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://samx.io/post/daddy-what-do-you-do-at-work/</guid>
      <description>Talking with Boy #1 about his day before bedtime.
They had 2 dentists come into class that day so he was really curious about what I do at work&amp;hellip;
Boy 1: Daddy, what do you do at work? Do you do math? Me: Yeah, math and computer programming Boy 1: How about English? Me: I have to write a lot, like emails and documentation and chats, so I guess you could say I do English too Boy 1: Like, you write sentences?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Go libraries: Minimize interface surface area</title>
      <link>http://samx.io/post/golang-minimize-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://samx.io/post/golang-minimize-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>When in doubt, leave it out
Jasmin Blanchette, The Little Manual of API Design
 Sometimes you want to abstract away the implementation of a component in your library, for example a logger. The typical approach for this is defining an interface that clients would then pass in.
So you think to yourself, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m such a nice person, I&amp;rsquo;m going to let my user pass in any logger of their choosing&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get hired</title>
      <link>http://samx.io/post/how-to-get-hired/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://samx.io/post/how-to-get-hired/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on the SendGrid Blog
I’m not great at on-the-spot thinking, so I’m handicapped off-the-bat in technical interviews — especially when I have to code on a white board. I’m at my best when I have time to prepare in advance. Last year I discovered a method which played to my strengths and landed me a job that I love.
Discovering the Briefcase Technique In 2012, I took a course on how to start a business called “Earn One Thousand Dollars On The Side” by Ramit Sethi, a business consultant.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>